Nir Gilad

Software Developer & Bioinformatician

Nir Gilad

Kibbutz Ein Gedi (Willing to Relocate)

0523-960-717

nir.gilad777@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/giladnir (Linkedin)

Nirol.github.io (Portfolio)

Skills

Data Science & ML: Multiple projects on my Github\ website.

<u>CS Experience mainly with:</u> Java, Python, Flask, Spring, Linux, R, SQL, Machine learning, Data Mining & Visualization, AWS.

<u>Bioinformatics Experience:</u> Pipeline development, Data analysis and Machine learning, Incorporating various tools and Databases into pipelines.

Experience

Self-Employed / Cryptocurrency Algorithmic Trade

June 2016 - Now

Developed and operated Cryptocurrency exchange trading bot. Scraping and tutoring projects.

Ben-Gurion University of the Negev / Teaching Assistant

October 2015 - September 2017 (2 years), Ben Gurion University

The National Institute for Biotechnology in the Negev /

Solved missing sequencing data with Machine Learning.

Bioinformatician January 2015 - July 2016 (1 year 7 months), Be'er Sheva

Developed tools and databases for the analysis of genomics datasets.

Analysis and visualization of large scale genomic data in R and Python.

Education

Ben-Gurion University MSc Computer Science (Bioinformatics) 94

The thesis expanded on the known dynamic programming tree reconciliation algorithm. Outstanding performance in machine learning, data mining, and computational biology courses.

Ben-Gurion University BSc Computer Science (Bioinformatics) 89.5

Graduated with honors. Excellent grades in the majority of courses: CS intro, data structures, system programming, and operating systems, as well as outstanding performance in Bioinformatics courses and a final project.